Guide to the New American Library Archive 1943-1962 MSS.070
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: New American Library, Editorial/Author Files
  - Leinster, Murray, "Operation Outer Space,", 1953-1958 (Box 54, Folder 1154)
  - LeMay, Alan, "Cattle Kingdom,", 1953-1956 (Box 54, Folder 1155)
  - Lemisch, Jesse, "Benjamin Franklin" (Anthology of selected writings), 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 1156)
  - Lentz, John, with Dr. Wheatley, general correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 54, Folder 1157)
  - Leonard, Jonathan, "Flight Into Space,", 1953-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1158)
  - Lerner, Allan Jay, "My Fair Lady,", 1956-1960 (Box 54, Folder 1159)
  - Leslie, Warren, "The Best Thing That Ever Happened,", 1952-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1160)
  - Lessing, Lawrence P., "The World of Chemistry,", 1954-1961 (Box 55, Folder 1161)
  - Lessing, Lawrence P., "The World of Chemistry,", 1955-1959 (Box 55, Folder 1162)
  - Levi, Carlo, "Christ Stopped at Eboli,", 1953-1955 (Box 55, Folder 1163)
  - Levin, Ira, "A Kiss Before Dying,", 1952-1959 (Box 55, Folder 1164)
  - Levin, Meyer, "The Young Lovers" ["Frankie and Johnnie"], 1951-1953 (Box 55, Folder 1165)
  - Levine, Irving R., "Main Street USSR,", 1959-1960 (Box 55, Folder 1166)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, "The Mind of an Assassin,", 1959-1961 (Box 55, Folder 1167)
  - Levy, ____, "Mathematics for More Than the Millions,", 1960 (Box 55, Folder 1168)
  - Lewis, Roy, "The Managers" ["The Men at the Top"], 1958-1961 (Box 55, Folder 1169)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, "Arrowsmith,", 1961 (Box 55, Folder 1170)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, general correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 55, Folder 1171)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, "In a Summer Season,", 1953-1957 (Box 55, Folder 1172)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, "The Tyranny of Sex" ["The Case of Mr. Crumb"], 1947-1956 (Box 55, Folder 1173)
  - Ley, Willie, "Satellites, Rockets, and Outer Space,", 1954-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1174)
  - Lindberg, Anne Morrow, "Gift From the Sea,", 1956-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1175)
  - Lindeman, Edward, general correspondence and reports, 1945-1950 (Box 56, Folder 1176)
  - Lindeman, Edward, general correspondence and reports, 1951-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1177)
  - Lindeman, Edward, "Basic Selections From Emerson,", 1947-1953 (Box 56, Folder 1178)
  - Lindeman, Edward, "Emerson: The Basic Writings of America's Sage,", 1946-1954 (Box 56, Folder 1179)
  - Lindeman, Edward, "Plutarch's Lives,", 1950-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1180)
  - Lindeman, Edward, "The Lindeman Chair,", 1953-1956 (Box 56, Folder 1181)
  - Linscott, Roger, general correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 56, Folder 1182)
  - Lippman, Walter, "The Public Philosophy,", 1945-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1183)
  - Lipsky, Elezear, "Kiss of Death,", 1948-1953 (Box 56, Folder 1184)
  - Lobsenz, Herbert, "Vangel Griffin,", 1961 (Box 56, Folder 1185)
  - Locke, Alain, "The Negro in American Culture,", 1950-1955 (Box 56, Folder 1186)
  - Locke, Alain, "The Negro in American Culture," ms., undated (Box 56, Folder 1187)
  - Loebsack, Theo, "Our Atmosphere,", 1959-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1188)
  - Loeff, Ted, "Mutch,", 1959-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1189)
  - Loeff, Ted, Philippine novel, 1958-1959 (Box 56, Folder 1190)
  - Lomax, Louis, "Civil Rights in America,", 1958-1959 (Box 56, Folder 1191)
  - Mahannah, Floyd, "The Broken Body" ["The Golden Goose"], 1950-1952 (Box 56, Folder 1192)
  - Mahannah, Floyd, "No Luck For a Lady" ["The Yellow Hearse"], 1950-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1193)
  - Mahannah, Floyd, "Stopover For Murder,", 1953-1956 (Box 56, Folder 1194)
  - Mailer, Norman, general correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1195)
  - Mailer, Norman, "Advertisements for Myself,", 1959-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1196)
  - Mailer, Norman, "Barbary Shore,", 1951-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1197)
  - Mailer, Norman, "The Deer Park,", 1954-1960 (Box 56, Folder 1198)
  - Mailer, Norman, "The Naked and the Dead,", 1948-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1199)
  - Mainwaring, Dan, "Hell Bent For Heaven,", 1959 (Box 56, Folder 1200)
  - Malamud, Bernard, "The Assistant,", 1957-1959 (Box 56, Folder 1201)
  - Malaparte, Curzio, "The Skin,", 1951-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1202)
  - Malory, Sir Thomas, "The Morte d'Arthur,", 1959-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1203)
  - Malthus, Thomas, Julian Huxley, and Frederick Osborn, "On Population: Three Essays,", 1959-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1204)
  - Manckiewicz, Don, "See How They Run,", 1951-1957 (Box 56, Folder 1205)
  - Mankowitz, Wolf, "Old Soldiers Never Die,", 1957-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1206)
  - Mann, Abby, "Judgment at Nuremberg,", 1961 (Box 56, Folder 1207)
  - Mann, Heinrich, "The Blue Angel,", 1959 (Box 56, Folder 1208)
  - Mann, Thomas, "The Confessions of Felix Krull, Confidence Man,", 1948-1957 (Box 56, Folder 1209)
  - March, William, "Company K,", 1957-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1210)
  - Margolis, Sidney, "The Consumer's Guide to Better Buying,", 1949-1953 (Box 56, Folder 1211)
  - Margolis, Sidney, "The Consumer's Guide to Better Buying,", 1954-1961 (Box 56, Folder 1212)
  - Margolis, Sidney, "How to Achieve Financial Security,", 1954-1956 (Box 56, Folder 1213)
  - Markandaya, Kamala, "Nectar in a Sieve,", 1956-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1214)
  - Markandaya, Kamala, "Some Inner Fury,", 1958-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1215)
  - Markowitz, Arthur, "The Daughter,", 1950-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1216)
  - Marks, Lawrence, "Women and Children Last,", 1959-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1217)
  - Marsh, Ngaio, general correspondence, 1953 (Box 57, Folder 1218)
  - Marsh, Ngaio, "Night at the Vulcan,", 1951-1956 (Box 57, Folder 1219)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, general correspondence, 1949-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1220)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, "Duchess Hotspur,", 1952-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1221)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, "The General's Wench,", 1952-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1222)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, "Kitty,", 1951-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1223)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, "Laird's Choice,", 1950-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1224)
  - Marshall, Rosamund, "The Temptress,", 1952-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1225)
  - Martin, Don, "Mad's Maddest Artist,", 1961 (Box 57, Folder 1226)
  - Martin, John Bartlow, "Butcher's Dozen,", 1950-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1227)
  - Martin, John Bartlow, "My Life in Crime,", 1952-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1228)
  - Marvin, H.M., et al, "You and Your Heart,", 1952-1959 (Box 57, Folder 1229)
  - Mason, Agnes Leckie, and Phyllis Chanian, "God's Wonderful World,", 1953-1954 (Box 57, Folder 1230)
  - Mason, Agnes Leckie, and Phyllis Chanian, "God's Wonderful World,", 1954-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1231)
  - Mason, Agnes Leckie, and Phyllis Chanian, "God's Wonderful World," ms., undated (Box 57, Folder 1232)
  - Mason, Richard, "The Shadow and the Peak,", 1958-1959 (Box 57, Folder 1233)
  - Mason, Richard, "The World of Susie Wong,", 1956-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1234)
  - Maugham, Somerset, "The Summing Up,", 1946-1959 (Box 57, Folder 1235)
  - Maurette, Marcelle, "Anastasia,", 1955-1959 (Box 57, Folder 1236)
  - Margaret Mead, general correspondence, 1951-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1237)
  - Margaret Mead, "Coming of Age in Samoa,", 1949-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1238)
  - Margaret Mead, "Cultural Patterns and Technical Change,", 1954-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1239)
  - Margaret Mead, "Growing Up in New Guinea,", 1952-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1240)
  - Margaret Mead, "Male and Female,", 1949-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1241)
  - Margaret Mead, "New Lives For Old,", 1956-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1242)
  - Margaret Mead, "Sex and Temperament", undated (Box 57, Folder 1243)
  - Medawar, P.B., "The Future of Man,", 1960-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1244)
  - Meier, Frederick, "Character Reading Made Easy,", 1954-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1245)
  - Melville, Herman, "Billy Budd,", 1960-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1246)
  - Melville, Herman, "Moby Dick,", 1955-1962 (Box 57, Folder 1247)
  - Mentor archaeological project, 1955-1956 (Box 57, Folder 1248)
  - Mentor philosophers, 1953-1956 (Box 57, Folder 1249)
  - Mentor records, 1957-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1250)
  - Mentor religious series, undated (Box 57, Folder 1251)
  - Merton, Thomas, 'The Seven Storey Mountain,", 1949-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1252)
  - Meyer, Gordon, "The Investment,", 1960 (Box 57, Folder 1253)
  - Meyers, ____, "Rechen Duden,", 1960 (Box 57, Folder 1254)
  - Michaelson, John, "Morning, Winter, and Night,", 1952-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1255)
  - Millard, Joseph, "Terror of the Outlaws,", 1957-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1256)
  - Miller, Floyd, "Better Be Damned,", 1958-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1257)
  - Miller, Floyd, "Listen, the Jackals!", 1957-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1258)
  - Miller, Floyd, "Scandale,", 1958-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1259)
  - Miller, Henry, general correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1260)
  - Miller, Henry, "A Devil in Paradise,", 1956-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1261)
  - Miller, Henry, "The Intimate Henry Miller,", 1952-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1262)
  - Miller, Henry, "Nights of Love and Laughter,", 1946-1954 (Box 57, Folder 1263)
  - Miller, Henry, "Nights of Love and Laughter,", 1955-1960 (Box 57, Folder 1264)
  - Miller, Max, "Holiday Street,", 1959-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1265)
  - Miller, Ron, "The Comics,", 1959-1960 (Box 58, Folder 1266)
  - Miller, Wade, general correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 58, Folder 1267)
  - Miller, Wade, "Calamity Fair,", 1950-1955 (Box 58, Folder 1268)
  - Miller, Wade, "Deadly Weapon,", 1947-1960 (Box 58, Folder 1269)
  - Miller, Wade, "Fatal Step,", 1947-1960 (Box 58, Folder 1270)
  - Miller, Wade, "Guilty Bystander,", 1947-1958 (Box 58, Folder 1271)
  - Miller, Wade, "Killer's Choice" ["Devil on Two Sticks"], 1949-1961 (Box 58, Folder 1272)
  - Miller, Wade, "Kiss Her Goodbye,", 1957-1960 (Box 58, Folder 1273)
  - Miller, Wade, "Murder Charge,", 1950-1961 (Box 58, Folder 1274)
  - Miller, Wade, "Shoot to Kill,", 1951-1956 (Box 58, Folder 1275)
  - Miller, Wade, "Uneasy Street,", 1948-1957 (Box 58, Folder 1276)
  - Miller, Wade, "With a Vengeance,", 1956 (Box 58, Folder 1277)
  - Milligan, Harold V., "Stories of Famous Operas,", 1954-1957 (Box 58, Folder 1278)
  - Millis, Walter, "A Military History of the United States" ["Arms and Men"], 1952-1961 (Box 58, Folder 1279)
  - Milton, Daniel L., "Great Stories From Asia,", 1958-1961 (Box 58, Folder 1280)
  - Milton, Daniel L. and William C. Clifford, "A Treasury of Modern Asian Stories,", 1961 (Box 58, Folder 1281)
  - Mirvish, Robert, "The Eternal Voyages,", 1953-1959 (Box 58, Folder 1282)
  - Mirvish, Robert, "A House of Her Own,", 1953-1957 (Box 58, Folder 1283)
  - Mitchell, Joseph, "McSorley's Wonderful Saloon,", 1945-1954 (Box 58, Folder 1284)
  - Mitford, Nancy, "The Blessing,", 1949-1958 (Box 58, Folder 1285)
  - Mock, Elizbeth, "Modern Architecture,", 1946 (Box 59, Folder 1286)
  - Moll, Elick, "Seidman and Son,", 1958-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1287)
  - Monash, Paul, "The Singin' Idol,", 1957-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1288)
  - Monsarrat, Nicholas, "Depends What You Mean by Love,", 1949-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1289)
  - Montagu, Ashley, "The Book of the Id,", 1958-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1290)
  - Montagu, Ashley, "Human Heredity,", 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1291)
  - Montgomery, Viscount of Alamein (Bernard Law), "Memoirs,", 1958-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1292)
  - Moore, Geoffrey, general correspondence, 1959 (Box 59, Folder 1293)
  - Moore, Harry, "20th Century Literature,", 1960-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1294)
  - Moore, Pamela, "And the Pigeons of St. Mark's,", 1960 (Box 59, Folder 1295)
  - Moravia, Alberto, general correspondence, 1950-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1296)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Bitter Honeymoon,", 1952-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1297)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "The Conformist,", 1951-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1298)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Conjugal Love,", 1950-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1299)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Fancy Dress Party,", 1951-1955 (Box 59, Folder 1300)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "A Ghost at Noon,", 1952-1956 (Box 59, Folder 1301)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Mistaken Ambitions" ['Wheel of Fortune"], 1952-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1302)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Roman Tales,", 1956-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1303)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "The Time of Indifference,", 1950-1955 (Box 59, Folder 1304)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Three Novels,", 1961 (Box 59, Folder 1305)
  - Moravia, Alberto, trilogy, 1957-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1306)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Two Adolescents,", 1950-1957 (Box 59, Folder 1307)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Two Women,", 1958-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1308)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "The Wayward Wife,", 1960-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1309)
  - Moravia, Alberto, "Woman of Rome,", 1949-1959 (Box 59, Folder 1310)
  - Morehead, Albert, general correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 59, Folder 1311)
  - Morehead, Albert, general correspondence and reader mail, 1946-1960 (Box 59, Folder 1312)
  - Morehead, Albert, "Crossword Puzzle Book,", 1958-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1313)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: additions, comments, endorsements, contest, 1949-1953 (Box 59, Folder 1314)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: contracts, legal, copyright, 1950-1955 (Box 59, Folder 1315)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: distribution, FTC ruling, production, promotion, 1950-1954 (Box 59, Folder 1316)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: correspondence and memos, 1946-1959 (Box 59, Folder 1317)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: 1955 rev. Edition, 1953-58, 1953-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1318)
  - Morehead, Albert, dictionary: sales in catholic schools, reader mail, research, 1950-1953 (Box 59, Folder 1319)
  - Morehead, Albert, games: contract bridge, crossword puzzle, 1947-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1320)
  - Morehead, Albert, games: Penguin Hoyle, Quiz Book, reader mail, 1945-1957 (Box 59, Folder 1321)
  - Morehead, Albert, "Hoyle's Rules of Games,", 1949-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1322)
  - Morehead, Albert, "New American College Vocabulary Builder,", 1958-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1323)
  - Morehead, Albert, "New American Webster Handy College Dictionary,", 1951-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1324)
  - Morehead, Albert, plot outlines for novels, 1959 (Box 59, Folder 1325)
  - Morehead, Albert, "Roget's Handy College Thesaurus in Dictionary Form,", 1956-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1326)
  - Morehead, Albert, "Samba,", 1950-1951 (Box 59, Folder 1327)
  - Morehead, Albert, synopses, 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1328)
  - Morehead, Albert, "University Thesaurus,", 1960 (Box 59, Folder 1329)
  - Morehead, Albert, "Vocabulary Builder,", 1959 (Box 59, Folder 1330)
  - Morgan, Joe [Gardner F. Fox], "Expense Account,", 1956-1959 (Box 59, Folder 1331)
  - Morgan, Joe [Gardner F. Fox], "The Roman and the Slave Girl,", 1957-1959 (Box 59, Folder 1332)
  - Morhaim, Victoria, general correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1333)
  - Morhaim, Victoria, "An American Marriage,", 1960 (Box 59, Folder 1334)
  - Morhaim, Victoria, "The Girl in the Gold Leather Dress,", 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1335)
  - Morhaim, Victoria, "Lovely Sammy,", 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1336)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, "Christopher Columbus, Mariner,", 1953-1961 (Box 59, Folder 1337)
  - Morley, Christopher, "Kitty Foyle,", 1947-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1338)
  - Morley, Christopher, "Thunder on the Left,", 1946-1951 (Box 60, Folder 1339)
  - Morley, Susan, "Making of a Mistress" ["Juniper Green"], 1948-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1340)
  - Morris, Donald R., "China Station,", 1951-1955 (Box 60, Folder 1341)
  - Morris, Robert T., "Fifty Years a Surgeon,", 1955-1957 (Box 60, Folder 1342)
  - Morris, Wright, "The Field of Vision,", 1957-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1343)
  - Morris, Wright, "Love Among the Cannibals,", 1957-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1344)
  - Motley, Willard, "Knock on Any Door,", 1948-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1345)
  - Motley, Willard, "Let No Man Write My Epitaph,", 1956-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1346)
  - Motley, Willard, "We Fished All Night,", 1951-1953 (Box 60, Folder 1347)
  - Mott, Frank Luther, "A Gallery of Americans,", 1950-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1348)
  - Muller, Herbert, "The Loom of History,", 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1349)
  - Muller, Herbert, "The Uses of the Past,", 1952-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1350)
  - Mulvihill, William, "The Mantrackers,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1351)
  - Murray, Don, "The Sensation,", 1959-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1352)
  - Murray, Marris, "The Color of Blood" ["The Fire Raisers"], 1953-1957 (Box 60, Folder 1353)
  - Mystery Writers of America, general correspondence, 1947-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1354)
  - Nablo, James Benson, "The Long November,", 1949-1954 (Box 60, Folder 1355)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir, and Vera Nabokov, "Laughter in the Dark,", 1949-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1356)
  - Nathan, Robert, "Portrait of Jennie,", 1947-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1357)
  - Neuvecalle, Jean, "The Vatican,", 1955 (Box 60, Folder 1358)
  - Newmeyer, Sarah, "Enjoying Modern Art,", 1954-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1359)
  - Nicholson, Margaret, "A Dictionary of American-English Usage,", 1956-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1360)
  - Nicole, "Les Lions Sont Laches,", 1956-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1361)
  - Nimier, Roger, "The Blue Hussar," "The Children of Circumstance,", 1952-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1362)
  - Nutting, Anthony, "Lawrence of Arabia,", 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1363)
  - Nye, Hermes, general correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1364)
  - Nye, Hermes, "Fortune is a Woman,", 1956-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1365)
  - Nye, Nelson, general correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1366)
  - Nye, Nelson, "Bandido,", 1956-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1367)
  - Nye, Nelson, "Maverick Marshall,", 1957-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1368)
  - Nye, Nelson, "The Overlanders,", 1956-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1369)
  - O'Brien, Robert, "Genius of the Spanish Theater,", 1961 (Box 60, Folder 1370)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, "A Good Man is Hard to Find,", 1955-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1371)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, "The Violent Bear It Away,", 1958-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1372)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, "Wise Blood,", 1952-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1373)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam, "The Stories of Liam O'Flaherty,", 1956-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1374)
  - Ohanian, Phyllis, "God's Wonderful World,", 1954-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1375)
  - O'Hara, John, "Appointment in Samarra,", 1953-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1376)
  - Olay, Lionel, general correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1377)
  - Olay, Lionel, "Dark Corners of the Night,", 1958-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1378)
  - Olay, Lionel, "The Heart of a Stranger,", 1956-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1379)
  - Olesha, Yuri, "The Wayward Comrades and the Commissars,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1380)
  - O'Neal, Charles, "The Cheka Story,", 1960 (Box 60, Folder 1381)
  - O'Neil, Russell, "This Too is My Son,", 1960 (Box 60, Folder 1382)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, "Desire Under the Elms,", 1953-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1383)
  - Opik, Ernest, "The Oscillating Universe,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1384)
  - Orkow, Ben, general correspondence, 1961 (Box 60, Folder 1385)
  - O'Rourke, Frank, general correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1386)
  - O'Rourke, Frank, "Ambuscade,", 1958-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1387)
  - O'Rourke, Frank, "Desperate Rider,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1388)
  - O'Rourke, Frank, "A Texan Came Riding,", 1957-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1389)
  - O'Rourke, Frank, "Violent Country,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1390)
  - Orwell, George, general correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1391)
  - Orwell, George, "Animal Farm,", 1953-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1392)
  - Orwell, George, "1984,", 1949-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1393)
  - Otto, Max, "Science and the Moral Lie,", 1946-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1394)
  - Oursler, Fulton, "Wonderful World of Books", undated (Box 60, Folder 1395)
  - Owen, Jack, "The Beach Bums,", 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1396)
  - Packer, Peter, "The Starr Faithful Story,", 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1397)
  - Padover, Saul K., general correspondence, 1945-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1398)
  - Padover, Saul K., "Thomas Jefferson on Democracy,", 1946-1961 (Box 60, Folder 1399)
  - Padover, Saul K., "Jefferson," rev. and abrid., 1951-1959 (Box 60, Folder 1400)
  - Padover, Saul K., "The Living U.S. Constitution,", 1952-1960 (Box 60, Folder 1401)
  - Padover, Saul K., "The Living U.S. Constitution," photos, 1953-1954 (Box 60, Folder 1402)
  - Palmer, Bruce, and John C. Giles, "Horseshoe Bend,", 1959-1961 (Box 61, Folder 1403)
  - Panduro, Leif, "Kick Me in the Traditions,", 1961 (Box 61, Folder 1404)
  - Pares, Sir Bernard, "Russia,", 1945-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1405)
  - Parkinson, C. Northcate, general correspondence, 1960 (Box 61, Folder 1406)
  - Parkman, Francis, "The Oregon Trail,", 1949-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1407)
  - Parks, Edd W., "Backwater,", 1956-1959 (Box 61, Folder 1408)
  - Pasternak, Boris, general correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1409)
  - Pasternak, Boris, "Doctor Zhivago,", 1959-1961 (Box 61, Folder 1410)
  - Pasternak, Boris, "Safe Conduct and Other Writings,", 1958-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1411)
  - Pater, Walter, "The Renaissance,", 1959 (Box 61, Folder 1412)
  - Paton, Alan, "Cry the Beloved Country,", 1955-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1413)
  - Paton, Alan, "Too Late the Phalarope,", 1955-1961 (Box 61, Folder 1414)
  - Patten, Lewis B., "Law of the Gun,", 1959-1961 (Box 61, Folder 1415)
  - Patten, Lewis, "Tarnished Star,", 1960 (Box 61, Folder 1416)
  - Patterson, Robert, general correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 61, Folder 1417)
  - Pavese, Cesare, "The Moon and the Bonfires,", 1952-1958 (Box 61, Folder 1418)
  - Payne, Robert, general correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1419)
  - Payne, Robert, "The Barbarian and the Geisha,", 1957-1959 (Box 61, Folder 1420)
  - Payne, Robert, "The White Pony,", 1959-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1421)
  - Pearl, Cyril, "The Girl With the Swansdown Seat,", 1956-1959 (Box 62, Folder 1422)
  - Pearl, Richard, general correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1423)
  - Pearl, Richard, "How to Know Minerals and Rocks,", 1952-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1424)
  - Pearl, Richard, "Successful Prospecting and Mineral Collecting,", 1957-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1425)
  - Peattie, Donald C., "Lives of Destiny,", 1951-1960 (Box 62, Folder 1426)
  - Pei, Mario, "The Story of Language,", 1959-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1427)
  - Pendell, Elmer, "Human Breeding and Survival,", 1953-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1428)
  - Peppard, Harold K., "Sight Without Glasses,", 1956-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1429)
  - Peters, Fritz, general correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 62, Folder 1430)
  - Peters, Fritz, "The Descent,", 1952-1956 (Box 62, Folder 1431)
  - Peters, Fritz, "Finistere,", 1950-1955 (Box 62, Folder 1432)
  - Peters, Fritz, "World Next Door,", 1949-1955 (Box 62, Folder 1433)
  - Peterson, Roger Tory, general correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 62, Folder 1434)
  - Peterson, Roger Tory, "How to Know the Birds,", 1946-1955 (Box 62, Folder 1435)
  - Peterson, Roger Tory, "How to Know the Birds,", 1956-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1436)
  - Petrovskaya, Kyra, "Kyra,", 1959-1960 (Box 62, Folder 1437)
  - Petry, Ann, "Country Place,", 1953-1960 (Box 62, Folder 1438)
  - Petry, Ann, "The Narrows,", 1953-1955 (Box 62, Folder 1439)
  - Petry, Ann, "The Street,", 1948-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1440)
  - Phipps, Helene, "San Rafael Story,", 1960 (Box 62, Folder 1441)
  - Pickthall, M.M., "The Meaning of the Glorious Koran,", 1952-1953 (Box 62, Folder 1442)
  - Pickthall, M.M., "The Meaning of the Glorious Koran,", 1954-1961 (Box 62, Folder 1443)
  - Pitigrelli [Dino Segre], "Cocaine,", 1948-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1444)
  - Pittenger, Ted, "Warrior's Return,", 1953-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1445)
  - Pitts, Walter, "The History of Scientific Thought,", 1958-1960 (Box 62, Folder 1446)
  - Plagemann, Bentz, "This is Goggle,", 1955-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1447)
  - Plenn, J.H., general correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 62, Folder 1448)
  - Plenn, J.H., "The Fastest Gun in Texas,", 1955-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1449)
  - Plenn, J.H., "Pancho Villa,", 1955-1956 (Box 62, Folder 1450)
  - Plenn, J.H., "Texas Hellion,", 1954-1959 (Box 62, Folder 1451)
  - Poe, Edgar Allen, "The Fall of the House of Usher and Other Tales,", 1960 (Box 62, Folder 1452)
  - Pollet, Elizabeth, "A Family Romance,", 1950-1952 (Box 62, Folder 1453)
  - Portnoy, Louis, and Jules Saltman, "Fertility in Marriage,", 1950-1956 (Box 62, Folder 1454)